When we are working via a freelancing platform with a client, in some cases,
عندما نعمل مع عميل من خلال منصة للعمل الحر، تجد العميل يحاول أحيانًا تجاوز المنصة
the client may reach out to you to bypass
والتواصل معك لتحويل المستحقات من حسابه البنكي إلى حسابك مباشرةً،
the platform and just to direct payment from their bank account to yours.
المنصة ولمجرد إرسال الدفع من حسابهم المصرفي إلى حسابك.
This is usually done to avoid the platform fee and just engage directly.
وعادةً ما يتم هذا لتجنب رسوم المنصة وللتعامل المباشر.
This might be very lucrative for you as a freelancer as well,
ويمكن لهذا أن يكون مربحًا جدًا لك أنت أيضًا كموظف حر
but it's surely not a good idea in more ways than one.
ولكنها بالتأكيد ليست فكرة جيدة لأكثر من سبب.
First of all, it is unethical and illegal to bypass the platform.
أولًا، تجاوز المنصة هو أمر غير أخلاقي وغير قانوني.
You accept the terms of the platform when you sign up,
فـأنت تقبل بشروط المنصة وأنت تنشئ حسابك عليها،
which locks you into the platform for
وهو ما يلزمك بالمنصة في أي من
transactions with any clients that you find on the platform,
تعاملاتك مع أي عميل تجده على المنصة
unless the client buys you out by giving a one-time fee,
إلا إذا اشترى العميل خروجك من المنصة بإعطائك مبلغ مالي يُدفع مرة واحدة
which is usually quite high.
وهو ما يكون مبلغ كبير عادةً.
Thirdly, you'll see yourself losing trust of the client by doing so,
ثانيًا، سوف تجد نفسك فاقدًا لثقة العميل بارتكاب مثل هذا الفعل
even if the client says to do that in the first place.
حتى وإن كان العميل هو من طلب منك ذلك أولًا.
After all, if one can cheat the platform,
فإذا كنت قادرًا على خداع المنصة
nothing stops them from cheating the client as well.
فلن يوقفك شيء عن خداع العميل أيضًا.
Then you put yourself in a very dangerous position,
وأنت بهذا تضع نفسك في موقف خطير جدًا
since now the client can pay you on his own terms
لأن العميل الآن يمكنه الدفع لك بشروطه هو
and there is no intermediary to manage disputes.
بدون وجود وسيط لحل النزاعات.
Lastly, if you are ethical in your working and thinking,
وأخيرًا، إذا كنت تتحرى الأخلاقيات في عملك وتفكيرك
client will definitely respect that in the long term.
فسوف يحترم العميل قطعًا هذا الأمر على المدى البعيد.
Not to mention, the satisfaction you will achieve of doing the right thing.
ناهيك عن الرضاء الذي سوف تشعر به حين تفعل الشيء الصحيح.